Guide to the Joseph Hart Papers MC.87
New York University Archives
Joseph Hart Papers
1930-1973
1961-1967
New York University Archives
Hart, Joseph T., Dr.
MC.87
0.5 Linear Feet in one manuscript box
Dr. Joseph T. Hart served as the curator and librarian at the Gould Memorial Library on the University Heights campus. The collection includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, publications, and reports regarding New York University and the School of Engineering and Science from 1930-1973.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of a report in folder 5, which is restricted. The report has been removed and placed in a folder directly behind folder 5 that is labeled as restricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by subject in two series:
Series I: General NYU Material
Series II: School of Engineering and Science
Biographical Note
Dr. Joseph T. Hart served as the curator and librarian at the Gould Memorial Library on the University Heights campus.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of materials collected by Dr. Joseph T. Hart regarding New York University and the School of Engineering and Science from 1930-1973. Materials include correspondence related to the Hall of Fame, the Institute of Medical Engineers, and the Katra-Black Student Group; newspaper clippings related to general university activities, and construction and opening of the Engineering library at the University Heights campus; pamphlets related to facilities funding and University Heights campus buildings; reports related to the total data processing requirements for NYU in 1965; proposals for facility funding; and a statement written by Hart in 1961 related to NYU's Program for Leadership and Services in the 1960s.
Newspapers.; Engineering; New York University. School of Engineering and Science; New York University -- Libraries
- Series I: General NYU Material, 1930-1973; 0.3 Linear Feet in one manuscript box
  Scope and Contents
  Series I includes Hart's statement on NYU's Program for Leadership and Service in the 1960s; correspondence related to the Hall of Fame, the Institute of Mechanical Engineers, and the Katra-Black Student Group; proposals written in 1965 related to funding the construction of a technology building at the University Heights Campus; a 1952 survey of the University Heights Library; a 1965 survey on the total data processing requirements of NYU; and pamphlets and clippings related to University Heights campus facilities and general university activities.
  - "A Statement for the Faculty and Staff on New York University's Program for Leadership and Services in the Sixties", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence on the Hall of Fame, 1930, 1955-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence on the Institute of Mechanical Engineers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence on the Katara-Black Student Group, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Heights Campus: Gould Memorial Library, Gould House and Tech II, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Conditions Governing Access
    A report from April 8, 1970 is restricted. The report has been removed and placed in a folder directly behind folder 5 that is labeled as restricted.
  - NYU Publications and Miscellaneous, 1951-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1961-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Survey of the University Heights Library of New York University by Alexander S. Preminger, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Total Data Processing Requirements of New York University: Study and Recommendations, Report, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A Proposal for a Graduate Science Facilities Grant in Connection with the Construction of Technology Building II at the University Heights Campus of New York University, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous materials extracted from the Proposal for a Graduate Science Facilities Grant, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: School of Engineering and Science, 1961-1970, undated; 0.2 Linear Feet in one manuscript box
  Series II includes correspondence and clippings related to the planning, construction, and opening of an engineering library at the University Heights campus between 1961 and 1965; and clippings and press releases related to general activities of and the history of the School of Engineering and Science.
  - History of the School of Engineering and Science, 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence on Engineering Library Planning and Construction, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings of the Engineering Library Planning, Construction, and Opening, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)